#### Contact

erinelszasz@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/erinelszasz-77b7b0a4 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Nursing

ICU

Healthcare

#### Certifications

Clinical Nurse Leader (CNL)

Acute/Critical Care Nurse - Adult, Pediatric, Neonatal (CCRN)

Certified Clinical Transplant Nurse (CPC)

Cardiac Surgery (Adult) (CSC)

# Erin Elszasz

Travel Nurse at Aya Healthcare

Cleveland, Ohio

## Summary

Experienced Registered Nurse and certified Clinical Nurse Leader with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital and health care industry. Skilled in nursing, patient safety, quality improvement and outcomes, and critical care with a passion for public and community health. Strong professional with a Master of Science in Nursing from Cleveland State University.

# Experience

Aya Healthcare

**Travel Nurse** 

April 2020 - Present (3 months)

Hackensack, New Jersey, United States

Crisis assignment caring for critically ill COVID-19 population. Float amongst intensive and intermediate care units.

Cleveland Clinic

8 years 6 months

Program Specialist, Transplant and Mechanical Circulatory Support November 2018 - April 2020 (1 year 6 months)

Cleveland/Akron, Ohio Area

Assistant Nurse Manager

January 2016 - November 2018 (2 years 11 months)

Cleveland/Akron, Ohio Area

Assistant Nurse Manager for J55 Cardiothoracic Surgical Intensive Care Unit. Supervise admissions and bed management of surgical cases in 76-bed CVICU. Facilitate multidisciplinary approach to care of heart and lung transplant recipients and patients on mechanical circulatory support. Provide direction, support, and evaluation to approximately 70 unit staff members. Assist in orientation of new personnel-including RNs, clinical technicians, and HUCs-ensuring continuing education, device certification, and annual competencies are performed. Identify and resolve issues affecting unit

personnel, patients, and families. Participate in quality improvement projects including CLABSI reduction initiative.

Flyout Registered Nurse Coordinator, Heart and Lung Organ Procurement Team

August 2014 - October 2016 (2 years 3 months)

Participate in organ procurement process by transporting organs from donor hospital to Cleveland Clinic while maintaining communication between Organ Procurement Organization, Procurement Team, Cleveland Clinic Surgeon, Anesthesia Staff, OR, CVICU, Transplant Coordinator, ground and/or air transportation, and Security. Assist with set-up of sterile field and surgical equipment, administer preservative fluids during and immediately post-harvest.

#### Registered Nurse

November 2011 - January 2016 (4 years 3 months)

Cardiothoracic Surgery Intensive Care Unit

Specialized in care of pre- and post-operative heart and lung transplant recipients, ventricular assist devices, intraaortic balloon pumps, and extracorporeal membrane oxygenation therapy. Certified as Vascular Access Resource Nurse and trained in ultrasound-guided peripheral IV insertion. Skilled in telemetry, intravenous therapy, central venous catheters, pulmonary and peripheral artery catheters, mechanical ventilation, dressing changes, sedation, tube feedings. Perform comprehensive assessments and interpret pertinent laboratory data. Relay significant changes, findings, and concerns to appropriate surgeons, nurse practitioners, and anesthesiologists. Serve as conduit for communication between health care team and client's family members. Function as Orientation Coach, training and supporting new hire RNs in patient care. Operate as Charge Nurse, maintaining status updates on each patient, plans of care, facilitating patient transfers to regular nursing floors and admissions to ICU from OR and stepdown. Serve as unit scheduler, organizing six-week schedules for 40+ RNs while accounting for adequate staffing with regards to experience and device coverage.

## Education

Cleveland State University

Master of Science in Nursing, Clinical Nurse Leader · (2016 - 2018)

Case Western Reserve University

Bachelor of Science in Nursing, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2007 - 2011)